Resume

Personal details

Name Ryan Jovani Junior Mben Bassaken

Email address bassakendev@gmail.com

Phone number +237 690439745

Address Douala Cameroon Douala-P14

Gender Male

Nationality Cameroonian

GitHub https://github.com/bassakendev

GitLab https//gitlab.com/Bassakendev

Telegram @Mr_Ryan



Profile

Hello, my name is Ryan!

I am a full-stack developer, distinguished not only by my ability to manage both front-end and back-end as well as mobile applications, but also by my fast learning abilities, my mastery of programming principles and the clarity of the code. My career has been anchored in remote work for 3 years now. Beyond simple development, my expertise extends to design (for a year), where I create web and mobile interfaces.

Laravel and flutter are the cornerstones of my technical toolbox. I learned development with them, I grew up with them and I have since specialized in these areas to the point of even proposing libraries based on them or inspired by them as well as participating in the evolution of certain packages.

My dedication to code quality and maintainability propelled me this year to the role of Project Manager, where I focus on best practices (use of linter, respect for design patterns, respect for conventions, etc.).

My freelance solicitation is a testament to the exponential growth of my performance. Having worked with a wide range of clients, I have developed a talent for delivering satisfactory solutions that meet needs. This experience has not only honed my technical skills, but also my ability to think critically and strategically about product development.

Education

Sep 2020 - Jul 2021 C-Baccalaureate

COPTAN, Douala

Oct 2021 - Dec 2023 Bac+3

ESIAC, Douala

I studied MSI engineering (Information Systems Management). At ESIAC

(Central African School of Engineering and Management).

May 2022 - Oct 2023 Mentalists (Canada) Attestation

Mentalist Company, Douala

Certificate of professional work as a full-stack developer

Jan 2021 - Sep 2022

Getsmarter Full-stack Laravel/flutter Attestation Getsmarter. Douala

I have been certified as a full-stack web and mobile developer (Laravel/flutter), Designer and analyst.

Employment

Feb 2023 - Jul 2024

Full-stack Developer

BantubeatGroup (Belgique), Douala

Brief description: Participate in development of BantuGroup social networks platforms (bantubeat, saloonprived and feat-link)

Responsibility:

- Participate in development (backend and frontend) of bantubeat.com: a beatstars like social network platform (sharing and sell beats)
- Participate in development (backend and frontend) of salonprived.com: a TikTok like social network platform (focused for Africans)
- Participate in development (backend and frontend) of feat-link.com: a Tinder like social network platform (focused for Africans)
- Participate in development (backend and frontend) of A unique administration panel for the three previous app

Technologies:

- · Laravel, MySQL and GraphQl for backend APIs
- Laravel, Flutter, ReactJS/NextJS and Tailwind, for frontend
- GitHub, JIRA, trello, jitsi, Google Meet for cooperation

Feb 2023 - Present

Mobile Developer

VCAM, Douala

Brief description: VCAM contacts me every time they want to build a product and need a senior engineer to analyze and build the product in collaboration with its developers.

Responsibility:

- Build mobile apps with Flutter
- Build backend APIs with Laravel (and only Laravel)

Technologies:

- Laravel, and MySQL for all VCAM backend APIs
- Flutter for mobile
- GitLab, Google Meet and Trello for cooperation

Mar 2023 - Apr 2024

Full-stack Developer

RNS (Cameroon - Garoua), Douala

Brief description: Analysis and development with Laravel and blade of a customer management website (with payment integration) for a television image broadcasting company like CANAL+.

Responsibility:

- Manage frontend with Laravel blade
- Manage backend with Laravel

Technologies:

Laravel (backend)

Laravel blade (frontend)

Jul 2024 - Present

Mobile developer

CGWEB (Canada), Douala

Brief description: Flutter + Spring Boot Global Developer Competition.

Responsibility:

- Mobile development with Flutter
- Designer with Figma

Technologies:

- Figma
- Flutter for mobile
- GitHub, Trello

Aug 2024 - Present

Full-stack Developer GetSmarter, Douala

Brief description: Developing a car sales application for Germans.

Responsibility:

- Manage backend with Laravel
- Manage frontend with Flutter

Technologies:

- Flutter (frontend)
- Laravel (backend)

Skills

Continuous learning Excellent

Analytical thinking Good

Concise communication Good

Attention to detail Excellent

Languages

French Fluent

English Good

Hobbies

- Music
- Football
- Meditation